<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Collections on InsightfulScript</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Collections on InsightfulScript</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/collections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Biometric Authentication in React Native Made Easy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react-native/react-native-biomatric/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react-native/react-native-biomatric/</guid>
      <description>Implementing Biometric Authentication in React Native Made Easy An extremely safe and practical method of user authentication is biometric authentication. To confirm a user&amp;rsquo;s identification, it uses physical or behavioural traits like fingerprints or facial recognition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React Native Modal- A Beginner&#39;s Guide to Creating User-Friendly Interfaces</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react-native/react-native-modal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react-native/react-native-modal/</guid>
      <description>React Native Modal- A Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Creating User-Friendly Interfaces Introduction React Native is a popular JavaScript framework that allows developers to create mobile applications for iOS and Android using a single codebase.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Tips to Optimize Landing Page Image Size</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/techs/tips-to-optimize-landing-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/techs/tips-to-optimize-landing-page/</guid>
      <description>12 Tips to Optimize Landing Page Image Size Image size optimization is essential for optimizing your landing page.&#xA;When images are too large, they can take longer to load and affect the overall performance of your page.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mastering React Native Styling Animation- Techniques, Tips, and Tricks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react-native/react-native-styling-animation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react-native/react-native-styling-animation/</guid>
      <description>Animations have the power to enhance the user experience in a mobile application. With React Native Styling Animation, you can add beautiful and interactive animations to your app. This powerful feature provides developers with an easy and effective way to create dynamic animations that can captivate users.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React Native Styleshee- A Comprehensive Guide for Beginners</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react-native/react-native-stylesheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react-native/react-native-stylesheet/</guid>
      <description>React Native Stylesheet: A Comprehensive Guide for Beginners Introduction React Native has become an incredibly popular tool for building cross-platform mobile applications, and for good reason. It allows developers to write code once and deploy it on multiple platforms, without sacrificing the native look and feel that users have come to expect.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React Native Firebase- A Comprehensive Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react-native/react-native-firebase/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react-native/react-native-firebase/</guid>
      <description>React Native Firebase: A Comprehensive Guide React Native Firebase is a powerful tool that combines the capabilities of Firebase, a mobile and web application development platform, with React Native, a popular framework for building mobile apps.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Customize Scrollbar in TailwindCSS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/tailwindcss/tailwindcss-scrollbar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/tailwindcss/tailwindcss-scrollbar/</guid>
      <description>How to Customize Scrollbar in TailwindCSS If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a way to improve the look and feel of your website, you might want to consider using Tailwind CSS. This popular utility-first CSS framework can help you style your website in a way that&amp;rsquo;s both easy and efficient.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailwind Z-Index - How to Use It with Examples</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/tailwindcss/tailwindcss-z-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/tailwindcss/tailwindcss-z-index/</guid>
      <description>Tailwind Z-Index: How to Use It with Examples If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever worked with web design and front-end development, you know that positioning elements on top of each other can be tricky.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React Router - A Simple Introduction For Beginners</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-router/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-router/</guid>
      <description>Understanding React Router: A Comprehensive Guide for Beginners If you&amp;rsquo;re a web developer who uses React, you know that building single-page applications can be a challenge. React Router is an essential tool for creating dynamic, client-side web applications.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scheduling python program using Cron Jobs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/python/schedule-python-scripts-as-cron-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/python/schedule-python-scripts-as-cron-jobs/</guid>
      <description>Scheduling python program using Cron Jobs Whether you are a website owner or just someone who needs to schedule execution of Python scripts, Cron jobs can be very helpful.&#xA;Introduction to Cron Jobs A cron job is a time-based task that is set to run at specific intervals.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best candlestick patterns that every trader should know</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/best-candlestick-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/best-candlestick-pattern/</guid>
      <description>Best candlestick patterns that every trader should know Candlestick charts are one of the most popular ways to visualize price data in the financial markets. They are easy to read and can provide valuable information about market trends and price movements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>react-calender - Building a calender app in React JS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-calender/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-calender/</guid>
      <description>React Calender In your react web app, managing and modifying dates is a common task. You may do things like add events or create reminders. You can do this by including a calendar in your web application.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reshaping Numpy Arrays- A Comprehensive Guide to Numpy Array Reshape</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/python/numpy/numpy-array-reshape/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/python/numpy/numpy-array-reshape/</guid>
      <description>Reshaping Numpy Arrays: A Comprehensive Guide to Numpy Array ReshapeNumpy Reshape You might frequently want to reshape an existing array into an array with a different number of dimensions while working with Numpy arrays.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python Array - Everything you need to know about</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/python/python-array/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/python/python-array/</guid>
      <description>Python Array This article will teach you how to use Python arrays. You&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to define them as well as the various methods for performing operations on them.&#xA;The article discusses arrays created by importing the array module in python.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your React App&#39;s Performance with useCallback() Hook</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-usecallbackhook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-usecallbackhook/</guid>
      <description>Boost Your React App&amp;rsquo;s Performance with useCallback() Hook Are you looking for ways to boost your React app&amp;rsquo;s performance? Look no further than the useCallback() hook! In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how this powerful hook can help improve your app&amp;rsquo;s speed and user experience.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React JS - useMemo hook in React</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-usememo-hook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-usememo-hook/</guid>
      <description>ReactJS - useMemo hook in React In software development, we&amp;rsquo;re typically fixated on performance improvements and ways to speed up our products so that users have a better experience.&#xA;One strategy for improving performance is memoization.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Beginner&#39;s Guide to React API Calls- Learn How to Make GET Requests with React</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-api-call/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-api-call/</guid>
      <description>A Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Guide to React API Calls: Learn How to Make GET Requests with React If you&amp;rsquo;re a developer working with React, you know how challenging it can be to keep up with all the APIs available.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React JS - useReducer hook in react</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-usereducer-hook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-usereducer-hook/</guid>
      <description>ReactJS - useReducer() hook in react Hooks in React introduced a new method of building and thinking about React apps. So far, one of the most popular hooks among developers is useReducer, which allows us to manage certain complex state manipulations and updates, and this is what we&amp;rsquo;ll learn about in this post.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React useLayoutEffect- A Comprehensive Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-uselayouteffect/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-uselayouteffect/</guid>
      <description>ReatJS - What is useLayoutEffect hook in react React is a well-known and rapidly developing JavaScript library in the web development industry. React is now an excellent alternative for developing interactive, modern real-world applications due to its ease of use and data-fetching capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React JS - Creating custom hooks in React</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-creating-custom-hooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-creating-custom-hooks/</guid>
      <description>ReactJS - Creating Custom hooks in React With the help of custom React hooks, you may provide your React applications additional, distinctive functionality.&#xA;Installing a third-party library designed to address your issue is frequently the simplest way to add a certain functionality to your application.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React JS - A complete guide to React refs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-createref-hook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-createref-hook/</guid>
      <description>ReactJS - A complete guide to refs and useRef() in React We will talk about how to directly manipulate DOM elements in React in this tutorial.&#xA;Although the React Framework constructs your components and abstracts your code from DOM manipulation, developers can still access it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React useContext Hook- Simplifying State Management in React</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-usecontext-hook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-usecontext-hook/</guid>
      <description>React useContext Hook: Simplifying State Management in React In a typical React application, data is passed top-down (from parent to child) by props, however this can be challenging for some prop types (such locale preference and UI theme), which are needed by numerous components that are nested at different levels within an application.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ReactJS - Understanding Higher Order Components in React</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-higher-order-components/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-higher-order-components/</guid>
      <description>ReactJS - Understanding Higher-Order Components in React **A function that takes a component and returns a new component is known as a higher-order component.**React&amp;rsquo;s higher-order components (HOCs) were inspired by JavaScript&amp;rsquo;s higher-order functions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mastering React Conditional Rendering- A Comprehensive Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-conditional-rendering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-conditional-rendering/</guid>
      <description>Mastering React Conditional Rendering: A Comprehensive Guide Conditional rendering is a crucial aspect of React that allows developers to render different components based on certain conditions. This feature helps to create dynamic and responsive user interfaces, making React a popular choice for building complex web applications.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Candlestick Pattern - Rising Window and Falling Window</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/rising-falling-window/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/rising-falling-window/</guid>
      <description>Candlestick Pattern - Rising Window and Falling Window All of the candle signals we have seen so far have been reversal. In fact, most candle signals are trend reversal. There are, however, a group of candle patterns that are continuation indicators.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Candlestick Pattern - Tower Top and Tower Bottom</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/tower-top-bottom-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/tower-top-bottom-pattern/</guid>
      <description>Candlestick Pattern - Tower Top and Tower Bottom Candlestick patterns are worth studying in depth, and while a strategy based purely on them will be unstable and unproductive, they can be a useful supplement to a whole trading system that incorporates other strategies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Candlestick Pattern - Dumpling Tops and Frypan Bottoms</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/dumpling-top-and-frypan-bottoms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/dumpling-top-and-frypan-bottoms/</guid>
      <description>Candlestick Pattern - Dumpling Tops and Frypan Bottoms Dumpling top and frypan bottoms. Someone must have been hungry when they thought of these names !!&#xA;Dumpling Top Candlestick Pattern Several Japanese candlesticks form the top structure of a dumpling.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Candlestick Pattern - Understanding Counterattack candlestick pattern</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/counter-attack-candlestick/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/counter-attack-candlestick/</guid>
      <description>Candlestick Pattern - Understanding Counterattack candlestick pattern There is no shortage of reversal indicators in technical analysis and candlestick patterns. The counterattack candlestick pattern is one such trend reversal indicator that many traders use to enter a positional trade.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenCV - Face Recognition using LBPH Classifier in C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv/opencv-creating-own-dataset-cpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv/opencv-creating-own-dataset-cpp/</guid>
      <description>OpenCV - Face Recognition using LBPH Classifier in C++ We learned HOW TO RECOGNIZE FACES in my OpenCV tutorial. Now, as shown below, we will gather and use our own data to recognize different faces using LBPH:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenCV - Face Detection using Haar cascade classifiers (C&#43;&#43;)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv/opencv-face-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv/opencv-face-detection/</guid>
      <description>OpenCV - Face Detection using Haar cascade classifiers (C++) The fact that computer vision makes very futuristic-sounding jobs a reality is one of the many reasons why it is a fascinating subject.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenCV - Removing Background from an image using GrabCut algorithm(C&#43;&#43;)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv/opencv-grabcut/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv/opencv-grabcut/</guid>
      <description>OpenCV - Removing Background from an Image using GrabCut Algorithm (C++) This may be appropriate for you if you are a newbie in the field of computer vision, as I am.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenCV - Image Segmentation using Watershed algorithm C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv/opencv-watershed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv/opencv-watershed/</guid>
      <description>OpenCV - Image Segmentation using Watershed algorithm C++ The watershed technique is a well-known segmentation algorithm that is particularly good for extracting touching or overlapping items in photographs.&#xA;Marker-based Watershed algorithm We must start with user-defined markers when using the watershed method.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenCV - Stereo Vision and Depth Estimation using C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv/opencv-stereo-image-depth-estimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv/opencv-stereo-image-depth-estimation/</guid>
      <description>OpenCV - Stereo Vision and Depth Estimation using C++ Have you ever wondered how robots travel by themselves, grip various things, or avoid collisions while moving? For such purposes, stereo vision-based depth estimate is a common method.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenCV - Understanding Hough Transform Using C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv/opencv-hough-line-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv/opencv-hough-line-detection/</guid>
      <description>OpenCV - Understanding Hough Transform Using C++ Before we can apply the Hough transform to images, we must first learn what a Hough space is, which we shall do through an example.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenCV - Understanding Convex Hull using C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv/opencv-convexhull/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv/opencv-convexhull/</guid>
      <description>OpenCV - Understanding Convex Hull using C++ Finding and analysing the forms present in an image is one technique to solving most computer vision problems, and getting the contour is one of them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenCV - Contour Detection Using C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv/contour-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv/contour-detection/</guid>
      <description>OpenCV - Contour Detection Using C++ Contour detection is an important task in computer vision, not only because of the obvious element of detecting contours of subjects in an image or video frame, but also because of the derivative processes associated with identifying contours.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenCV - Understanding Canny Edge Detection Using C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv/canny-edge-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv/canny-edge-detection/</guid>
      <description>OpenCV - Understanding Canny Edge Detection Using C++ Edge detection is a type of image processing that identifies the borders (edges) of objects or regions inside a picture. The edges of an image are one of the most important aspects of it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenCV - Understanding Low Pass And High Pass Filter using C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv/opencv-low-high-pass-filter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv/opencv-low-high-pass-filter/</guid>
      <description>OpenCV - Understanding Low Pass And High Pass Filter using C++ In the past post, we took in a few basic insights regarding the Fourier change and why it merits learning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenCV dft() - Fourier Transform using C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv-fourier-transform-cpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv-fourier-transform-cpp/</guid>
      <description>OpenCV Fourier Transform using C++ In OpenCV, the idea of Fourier Transform is used in a lot of the processing you do on pictures and videos.&#xA;Joseph Fourier was a French mathematician who worked in the 18th century, discovering and popularising several mathematical concepts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MLOps - Beginners Guid to MLOps,What It Is, and How to Implement It</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/machine-learning/mlops/what-is-mlops/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/machine-learning/mlops/what-is-mlops/</guid>
      <description>MLOps: A Beginners Guid to MLOps We were all studying about the software development lifecycle (SDLC) until recently, and how it goes from requirement elicitation to designing, programming, testing, deployment, and maintenance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehansive Guid to React Native Elements</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react-native/react-native-elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react-native/react-native-elements/</guid>
      <description>A Comprehansive Guid to React Native Elements React Native Elements (RNE) are a cross-platform user interface toolkit. These elements may now be utilised on the web, and your codebase can be shared between both React Native and React web projects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python Class Method Decorator- A Comprehensive Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/python/python-class-method-decorator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/python/python-class-method-decorator/</guid>
      <description>Python Class Method Decorator: A Comprehensive Guide Python is a powerful programming language that supports many features that make programming easier and more efficient. One of these features is the class method decorator.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Social Media Automation Tools</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/seo/social-media-automation-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/seo/social-media-automation-tools/</guid>
      <description>Best Social Media Automation Tools In the previous two decades, marketing has changed dramatically.To achieve customer loyalty, businesses must now be able to think on their feet.According to social media statistics, automation of digital marketing techniques, particularly social media, is critical.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React Native WebView Starter Guid</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react-native/react-native-webview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react-native/react-native-webview/</guid>
      <description>WebViews in React Native allow access to any online site from within the mobile app.&#xA;In a React Native project, the WebView component is used to load webpages. It used to be included in React Native out of the box, but it has since been removed from the core and added to the React Native Community libraries; for additional information, see The Slimmening proposal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top HTML &amp; CSS Courses - Learn HTML &amp; CSS Online</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/reviews/best-html-online-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/reviews/best-html-online-course/</guid>
      <description>Top HTML,CSS online courses for Beginner From beginner to advanced, the top online courses for learning HTML and CSS will help you enhance your website design and development skills.&#xA;The essential coding languages for web design and development are HTML and CSS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Guide to React Native Navigation Stack- Best Practices and Tips</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react-native/react-native-navigation-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react-native/react-native-navigation-stack/</guid>
      <description>A Comprehensive Guide to React Native Navigation Stack: Best Practices and Tips React Native Navigation Stack is an essential component for building mobile applications using React Native. It provides a flexible and powerful navigation solution that can help you create intuitive and easy-to-use interfaces for your users.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kaggle Data Science Projects for Beginners</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/machine-learning/kaggle-data-science-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/machine-learning/kaggle-data-science-projects/</guid>
      <description>Kaggle Data Science Projects for Beginners Introduction Kaggle has established itself as one of the most essential stepping stones for students and professionals interested in Data Science these days.&#xA;Kaggle features a wealth of online resources to aid in the learning of Data Science.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Machine Learning Projects For Beginners with Source Code [2021]</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/machine-learning/machine-learning-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/machine-learning/machine-learning-projects/</guid>
      <description>Best Machine Learning Projects As Artificial Intelligence (AI) continues to advance at a breakneck pace in 2021, mastering Machine Learning (ML) will become increasingly vital for all players in the field.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nodejs- forEach loop cheatsheet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/javascript/nodejs-foreach-loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/javascript/nodejs-foreach-loop/</guid>
      <description>Nodejs- forEach loop cheatsheet You can use looping to run through each item in an array and customise and output each one as you see fit. Loops are a crucial tool for rendering arrays in JavaScript, just as they are in any other programming language.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Guide to Auto-Encoders in Neural Networks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/neural-network/auto-encoders/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/neural-network/auto-encoders/</guid>
      <description>A Comprehensive Guide to Auto-Encoders in Neural Networks&amp;quot; In our last section we have seen what is ResNet and how to implement it. In this article we will look at AutoEncoders and how to implement it in PyTorch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everything you need to know about Python Pandas Data Profiling</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/python/pandas-data-profiling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/python/pandas-data-profiling/</guid>
      <description>What is Pandas Data Profiling ? The Pandas library has a large number of functions. It aids in data manipulation and offers a diverse set of features for practically any activity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best SQL online Courses To Enroll in 2022</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/reviews/best-sql-online-courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/reviews/best-sql-online-courses/</guid>
      <description>Best SQL online courses To enroll Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a beginner or an established user, the top online SQL courses make it straightforward and uncomplicated to increase your understanding in Structured Query Language (SQL).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Machine Learning ?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/machine-learning/what-is-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/machine-learning/what-is-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>What is Machine Learning ? According to Wikipedia:&#xA;Machine learning is a scientific study of algorithm and statistical model of computer system.&#xA;That is machine learning is used to perform certain tasks without using any human interaction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Three Mountain Top Candlestick Pattern(Buddha Top)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/three-mountain-top/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/three-mountain-top/</guid>
      <description>The Three Mountain Top Candlestick Pattern The three mountain top/Buddha Top is a technical analysis chart pattern that predicts a price reversal in an asset. A three mountain top, signals that the asset is no longer rallying and that lower prices are approaching.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ResNet -  Understanding the Revolutionary Neural Network Architecture for Deep Learning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/neural-network/resnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/neural-network/resnet/</guid>
      <description>ResNet: Understanding the Revolutionary Neural Network Architecture for Deep Learning ResNet (Residual Network) is a powerful convolutional neural network architecture that has revolutionized the field of deep learning. It was introduced in a research paper by Microsoft Research Asia in 2015 and has since become one of the most popular deep learning models due to its high accuracy and efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Javascript Regex cheatsheet 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/javascript/javascript-regex-cheat-sheat-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/javascript/javascript-regex-cheat-sheat-2021/</guid>
      <description>Javascript Regex Cheatsheet A Regular Expression (RegEx) is a string of characters that defines a search pattern. Regex can save you hundreds of lines of code and can be used with Javascript or any programming language (and even CLI tools)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) using Python</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/neural-network/cn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/neural-network/cn/</guid>
      <description>What is Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) In our previous article we have discussed how a simple neural network works.The problem with fully conntected neural network is that they are computationally expensive.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) using PyTorch</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/neural-network/cnn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/neural-network/cnn/</guid>
      <description>Implementing Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) in Pytorch In this turorial, we’ll go through the basic ideas of PyTorch starting at tensors and computational graphs and finishing at the Variable class and the PyTorch autograd functionality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Stochastic Gradient Descent Descent (SGD) with python</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/machine-learning/sgd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/machine-learning/sgd/</guid>
      <description>Stochastic Gradient Descent (SGD) with Python Stochastic gradient descent or SGD is very popular and powerful algorithm used in machine learning. Stochastic Gradient Descent (SGD) is an iterative algorithm which is used to compare various solution till the optimum solution is not found.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Three White Soldiers Candlestick Pattern</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/three-white-soliders/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/three-white-soliders/</guid>
      <description>Understanding Three White Soldiers Candlestick Pattern After a downtrend, the bullish three white soldiers chart pattern can be useful in predicting a price reversal. Understand this candlestick pattern and how to trade it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating Responsive Drawer using Material-UI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/material-ui-responsive-drawer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/material-ui-responsive-drawer/</guid>
      <description>React Tutorial : Creating responsive Drawer using Material-UI In this article we are going to build a responsive Drawer which adjust itself according to screen size using material-ui framework. If you are new visit here for installing and getting started with Material-UI.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating Social Card using React and Material UI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-social-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-social-card/</guid>
      <description>React Tutorial - Creating a social card using Material UI In this article we will create a simple social card using react&amp;rsquo;s materail UI framework.&#xA;The idea is to create 3 statless component namely SocialCard,CardFront,CardBack.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understand React Stateful and Stateless components</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-statefull-stateless/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-statefull-stateless/</guid>
      <description>React js components : Stateful vs stateless What is state ? State is an object which is declared inside the constructor method of the class.They are mutable and are used to interact between different component of the class.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding State and Props in React</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-state-props/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-state-props/</guid>
      <description>What are state and props in Reactjs In React js we develop different component to develop complex UI.To create dataflow between different component React uses state and porps. Because of state and props it is able to render component with dynamic data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenCV - Detecting corner location in subpixel(cornerSubPix()) using C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv/corernsubpixel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv/corernsubpixel/</guid>
      <description>OpenCV - Detecting corner location in subpixel(cornerSubPix()) using C++ A digital photo&amp;rsquo;s smallest component is called a &amp;ldquo;pixel&amp;rdquo;. Between pixel information is just inaccessible to the human sight. There are some applications that require more accuracy than a camera can provide.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Coding Apps for iOS and ipad0S</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/reviews/best-coding-app-ios-ipados/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/reviews/best-coding-app-ios-ipados/</guid>
      <description>Best Coding Apps for iOS and ipadOS The code has led to some of the world&amp;rsquo;s most innovative technologies. While all coders strive to enhance their skills, those who can code on the go will have an advantage over their competitors in this competitive field.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Customize Your GNOME Desktop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/linux/gnome-customize/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/linux/gnome-customize/</guid>
      <description>Customize Your GNOME Desktop A lot of people prefer GNOME&amp;rsquo;s minimalist design, which is quite straightforward and streamlined for a Linux GUI. In spite of its simplicity, GNOME may be customised to suit your needs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>calHist() - Calculate histogram using openCV and C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv/calculate-histogram/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv/calculate-histogram/</guid>
      <description>calHist() - Calculate histogram using openCV and C++ In practically every element of computer vision, histograms are used. For threshold, we employ gray-scale histograms. For white balance, we employ histograms. For object tracking in photos, such as with the CamShift technique, we use colour histograms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Best Machine Learning Libraries You Should Know in 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/reviews/machine-learning-libraries-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/reviews/machine-learning-libraries-2021/</guid>
      <description>7 Best Machine Learning Libraries You Should Know in 2021 Machine learning is currently the most talked-about topic in artificial intelligence.&#xA;Engineering, medicine, business, social science, and other professions are all affected.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenCV - Image Rotation using C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv/image-rotation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv/image-rotation/</guid>
      <description>OpenCV - Image Roatation using C++ Image editing is becoming increasingly popular as mobile phones have built-in capabilities that allow you to crop, rotate, and do other things with your images.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenCV - Fill Contour using C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv/fill-contours-cpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv/fill-contours-cpp/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Have you ever seen lines drawn around mountain ranges and elevations on topographical maps? Topographical contours are the names given to these lines. They provide an elevation profile of a terrain.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opencv - Harris Corner Detector using C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv-corner-harris-cpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/opencv-corner-harris-cpp/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The Harris Corner Detector is a corner detection operator frequently used in computer vision algorithms to extract corners and infer image characteristics. Chris Harris and Mike Stephens invented it in 1988 after improving Moravec&amp;rsquo;s corner detector.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python Data Structure Cheat Sheet- Your Complete Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/python/python-data-structure-cheat-sheet-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/python/python-data-structure-cheat-sheet-2021/</guid>
      <description>Python Data Structure Cheat Sheet: Your Complete Guide Python is a popular programming language that is widely used in various fields such as data science, machine learning, web development, and more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parallel Programming with C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/parallel-programming-stl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/cpp/parallel-programming-stl/</guid>
      <description>C++17 - New Parallel Algorithm of STL C++17 introduces parallel algorithms. However, there aren&amp;rsquo;t many implementations where the additional functionalities can be used.&#xA;The concept is straightforward. More than 100 algorithms are included in the Standard Template (STL) for searching, counting, and manipulating ranges and their constituents.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three Black Crows - Candlestick Pattern</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/three-black-crow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/three-black-crow/</guid>
      <description>Three Black Crows Candlestick Pattern The term &amp;ldquo;three black crows&amp;rdquo; refers to a bearish candlestick pattern that may indicate an uptrend&amp;rsquo;s reversal. Candlestick charts depict a security&amp;rsquo;s opening, high, low, and closing prices for the day.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Upside Gap Two Crows Candlestick Pattern for Crypto Trading</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/upside-gap-two-crows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/upside-gap-two-crows/</guid>
      <description>Understanding the Upside Gap Two Crows Candlestick Pattern for Crypto Trading When it comes to crypto trading, technical analysis plays a crucial role in identifying profitable trading opportunities. One such technical analysis tool is candlestick patterns, which help traders predict market trends based on past price movements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bullish And Bearish Belt Hold Line Candlestick Pattern</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/belt-hold-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/belt-hold-line/</guid>
      <description>Belt Hold Line Candlestick Pattern Belt Hold is candlestick pattern is considered as a modest reversal pattern that can suggest a bearish or bullish trend reversal depending on the pattern and direction of the trend it appears.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Chrome Flags to enable in 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/techs/top-10-chrome-flags-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/techs/top-10-chrome-flags-2021/</guid>
      <description>Top 10 Chrome Flags to enable in 2021 Google Chrome is the most used browser. It&amp;rsquo;s Excellent choice, whether you are using an Android phone, Mac or Windows PC. The Chrome stable is terrific on its own, but it&amp;rsquo;s not for power users.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is GitHub Copilot- Everything you need to know</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/reviews/github-copilot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/reviews/github-copilot/</guid>
      <description>What is GitHub Copilot- Everything you need to know OpenAI and GitHub launched a technical preview for a new AI tool called Copilot. It lives within Visual Studio Code and autocompletes code snippets.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding tweezer top and tweezer bottom candlestick pattern</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/tweezer-candle-stick-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/tweezer-candle-stick-pattern/</guid>
      <description>Understanding Tweezer Top and Bottom candlestick Pattern This guide will explain Tweezer Top candlesticks and Bottom candlesticks and how traders use them to detect market shifts.&#xA;We will examine the relationship between tweezer top and tweezer bottom candlesticks, how to find these formations on charts, and how they indicate directional movement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple App Tracking Transparency Features - Complete Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/techs/apple-app-tracking-transparency-feature/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/techs/apple-app-tracking-transparency-feature/</guid>
      <description>Apple App Tracking Transparency Features - Complete Guide Apple&amp;rsquo;s latest iOS 14.5, and iPadOS 14.5, introduced App Tracking Transparency. Apple states that App Tracking Transparency allows you to control which apps can track your activity across different companies&amp;rsquo; apps or websites.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Javascript Beginners Tips and Best Practices 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/javascript/javascript-beginner-tip-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/javascript/javascript-beginner-tip-2021/</guid>
      <description>Javascript Beginners Tips and Best Practices 2021 I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss JavaScript tips, tactics, and best practises for beginners that I use and find valuable in this blog.&#xA;Using Numeric Separator When dealing with enormous numbers, this is one of the most commonly utilised operators.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harami Candlestick Pattern- Everything you need to know about</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/harami-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/harami-pattern/</guid>
      <description>Harami Candlestick Pattern Before you start wondering, the name ‘Harami&amp;rsquo; does not refer to the Hindi word harami 😜. It&amp;rsquo;s thought to be an old Japanese word for &amp;ldquo;pregnancy.&amp;rdquo; When you see the candlestick formation, you&amp;rsquo;ll appreciate how intuitive this word is.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inverted Hammer Candlestick Pattern</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/inverted-hammer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/inverted-hammer/</guid>
      <description>Inverted Hammer Candlestick Pattern When it comes to trading, knowing how to recognize potential reversals will help you maximize your profits. One such signal that can assist you in identifying new trends is the inverted hammer candlestick pattern.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shooting Star Candlestick Pattern - Everthing you need to know</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/shooting-star/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/shooting-star/</guid>
      <description>Understanding the Shooting Star Candlestick Pattern When the term &amp;ldquo;Shooting Star&amp;rdquo; is mentioned, many envision a celestial object descending towards the earth&amp;rsquo;s surface. In the realm of Technical Analysis, however, a shooting star takes on a different meaning—it represents a bearish candlestick pattern characterized by a long upper shadow and the absence of a lower shadow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doji Star Candlestick Pattern - Everything you need to know about</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/everything-you-need-to-know-about-doji-star/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/everything-you-need-to-know-about-doji-star/</guid>
      <description>Candlestick Pattern - Everything you need to know about Doji Star Consider the market conditions when the buying trend is strong, but some traders also expect the current trend to reverse; this is why they sell.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Javascript String Methods Cheat Sheet 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/javascript/javascript-string-methods-cheat-sheet-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/javascript/javascript-string-methods-cheat-sheet-2021/</guid>
      <description>Javascript String Methods Cheat Sheet 2021 Use these JavaScript string methods to easily perform character manipulation.&#xA;When programming in JavaScript, you often come across scenarios that require string manipulation. For example, when retrieving email , you may need to convert all characters to lowercase or use regular expressions to check if the entered password meets conditions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Buy Cryptocurrency in India</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/how-to-buy-cryptocurrency-in-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/how-to-buy-cryptocurrency-in-india/</guid>
      <description>How to Buy Cryptocurrency in India Cryptocurrency has a tale of distrust and strict regulation in India. The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) and the Ministry of Finance have listed the potential use of volatility for investors&amp;rsquo; dangerous and illegal activities as their concerns.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evening Star Candlestick Pattern</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/evening-star/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/evening-star/</guid>
      <description>Evening Star Pattern The evening star candlestick pattern is the bearish counterpart of the morning star pattern in technical analysis. Because the evening star pattern is a top reversal, it should be acted upon if it occurs after an uptrend.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Merge sort algorithm</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/merge-sort-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/merge-sort-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>Understanding Merge Sort Algorithm Merge sort is a sorting algorithm based on &amp;ldquo;divide and conquer&amp;rdquo; technology. It is one of the most efficient classification algorithms.&#xA;In this blog, you will learn about the working principle of the merge sort algorithm, the merge sort algorithm, its time and space complexity, and its implementation in various programming languages such as C++, Python, JavaScript and Java.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Window 11 - All new Feature you need to know about</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/reviews/windows-11-is-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/reviews/windows-11-is-here/</guid>
      <description>Windows 11 - All new features Windows has always been the scene of global innovation. It has always been the backbone of global companies and a place where aggressive startups have become household names.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morning Star Candlestick Pattern</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/morning-star/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/morning-star/</guid>
      <description>Candlestick Pattern - Morning star For a long time, investors have been carefully studying the candlestick patterns that appear in the price trajectory. This is to predict the future. These areconsidered price signals in technical analysis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beginner Guid to Snap and Snap Store</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/linux/beginners-guid-to-snap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/linux/beginners-guid-to-snap/</guid>
      <description>Beginner guide to Snapcraft,Snap,Snapd and Snap Store Package Manager is a set of integrated services that make it easy to install, update, remove, and configure packages/programs on computers.&#xA;Especially with regard to the linux operating system, you can choose from a wide range of package managers, such as Pacman(Arch/Manjaro), apt(Ubuntu/Debian), yum(Red Hat/Cent Os),dnf(Fedora).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Piercing Line Candlestick Pattern</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/piercing-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/piercing-pattern/</guid>
      <description>Piercing line pattern For each bearish pattern, there is also a bullish pattern. So previously we have seen a bearish pattern - The Dark Cloud Cover. Now its counterpart is the bullish piercing line pattern.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dard Cloud Cover - Candlstick Pattern</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/dark-cloud-cover/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/dark-cloud-cover/</guid>
      <description>Dark Cloud Cover Candlestick Pattern What it is? A dark cloud cover is a bearish reversal candlestick pattern in which a falling candle (usually black or red) has an opening price higher than the closing price of the previous rising candle (usually white or green), and then the closing price is lower than the middle of the rising candle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Candle Stick Pattern- The Engulfing Pattern</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/the-engulfing-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/the-engulfing-pattern/</guid>
      <description>Engulfing Candlestick Pattern for Stock/Crypto Trading Before entering Engulfing pattern, you should know the following &amp;hellip;&#xA;The main goal of trading is to determine who &amp;ldquo;can&amp;rdquo; control the price and then trade in that direction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Downloading YouTube videos using Python</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/python/downloading-youtube-video-using-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/python/downloading-youtube-video-using-python/</guid>
      <description>Tutorial- Downloading YouTube videos using Python Requirements Python (Obvious) pytube Installing pip install pytube Downloading Youtube video After installing pytube, return to the text editor, open the Python file and import pytube:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hanging Man Candlestick Pattern</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/hanging-man-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/hanging-man-pattern/</guid>
      <description>Hanging Man Candlestick Pattern for Stock/Crypto Trading What is Hanging Man Candlestick Pattern? Hanging Man is a bearish reversal candlestick pattern with a longer lower shadow and smaller real body. This candlestick pattern appears at the end of an uptrend, indicating further weakness in price movements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Linux distros of 2021 for beginners, mainstream and advanced users</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/reviews/top-linux-distros-for-beginners/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/reviews/top-linux-distros-for-beginners/</guid>
      <description>Best Linux distros of 2021 for beginners, mainstream and advanced users Looking for a new Linux experience? Get to know the best Linux distribution for all user levels, from beginners to experts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hammer Candlestick Pattern</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/hammer-signal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/hammer-signal/</guid>
      <description>Hammer Candlestick pattern What is a hammer candlestick? Traders in the financial market(crypto/forex/stock) often use candlestick charts as a good visual aid to analyze and monitor the performance of a specific price in a given time period.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>winget: Package manager for windows</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/softwares/windows/windows-package-mangaer-winget/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/softwares/windows/windows-package-mangaer-winget/</guid>
      <description>Winget Package Manger for Windows If you have ever used any time today, then you will be familiar with the idea of the package manager. When I use it to switch to , I might miss that package manager very much.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Every thing you need to know about cryptocurrencies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/every-thing-to-know-about-cryptocurrency/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/every-thing-to-know-about-cryptocurrency/</guid>
      <description>Everything you need to know about Cryptocurrencies In recent years, the popularity of cryptocurrencies such as Bitcoin, Dogecoin, and Ethereum has increased. Many new terms and concepts have been introduced to the public.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React 18 is out !</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-18-alpha/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/react-18-alpha/</guid>
      <description>React 18 is Out! react core team recently released an alpha version of react18. this version pays more attention to user experience and internal architecture changes, including adaptive concurrency functions,it gives you more control over dom rendering events.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React Tutorial - Creating a simple weather app using React and Material UI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/weather-app-using-react/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/react/weather-app-using-react/</guid>
      <description>React Tutorial - Creating weather App using Material UI In this article we will be building a weather app using react js material UI framework. We will also be using openweathermap API for fetching the weather data from the site.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Crypto currencies you may want to invest in</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/crypto-currency-to-invest-in-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/crypto/crypto-currency-to-invest-in-2021/</guid>
      <description>5 Crypto you should watch in 2021 The cryptocurrency has exploded in popularity and widespread awareness. Part of the reason is that the value of some of these tokens has skyrocketed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Android VPN browsers for privacy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/techs/best-android-browser-for-privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/techs/best-android-browser-for-privacy/</guid>
      <description>Best Android VPN browsers for privacy Use these Android web browsers that come with a free built-in VPN to enhance your privacy and security.&#xA;A virtual private network (VPN for short) encrypts your internet activity and hides your location.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starter guid to SSH (Secure Shell)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/starter-guid-to-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Hatim Master)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/collections/programming/starter-guid-to-ssh/</guid>
      <description>Starter guid to SSH What is SSH? SSH or Secure Shell allows people to access your server remotely. It uses encryption technology to ensure that all communications to and from the server are encrypted.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
